(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone, welcome
back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're bringing
you an advanced lesson
for all of our advanced
learners out there.
- That's right, and in this lesson,
we're visiting a history class.
- Yes, we're gonna be talking
about a very interesting topic
that's known around the world,
which is International Workers' Day.
- That's right, and we're
going to learn a little bit
about the history of the workers'
movement in the United States.
- Right, but we're also gonna be taking a
look at some great words, and of course,
a little bit more advanced
or complicated structures.
- That's right, so I guess
without further ado,
we can get started with the dialogue.
(upbeat music)
- All right, everyone, settle down.
Let's get started.
As you know, an important aspect
of becoming a good citizen is understanding
the genesis of our legal system.
It's not enough to
simply memorize our laws.
It's necessary that we comprehend
why and how they were formed.
This brings me to our topic for today.
Does anyone know what
we celebrate on May 1st?
- Sinkered in my oh?
(audience laughing)
- No, that's, that's May
5th in Spanish, James.
No wonder you're failing my Spanish class.
No, May 1st is international workers' day.
- Do we get a day off from school in?
- No, it is not considered
to be a national holiday
here in the US, but
in other countries it is.
- Oh man.
- In the 19th century, working
conditions were appalling
with workers being forced to
work 10, 12 and 14 hours a day.
Support for the eight hour workday movement
was growing rapidly, despite the indifference
and hostility of many union leaders.
And by April 1886, 250,000 workers
were involved in the May Day movement.
Previous legislative attempts
to improve working conditions
had failed, so labor organizers
took drastic measures.
They passed the
resolutions, stating that eight
hours would constitute
a legal day's work.
And on May 1st, 1886,
the resolution took effect.
- Cool, is that why we
only work eight hours now?
- Yes, but the happy
ending came at a high price.
On May 3rd, 1886, police
fired into a crowd of strikers
at the McCormick Reaper
Works Factory, killing four
and wounding many, a
mass meeting was called
for the next day to
protest the brutality.
- And then what happened?
- Well, as we say, the rest is history.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so we were in a history class
and we learned something
new, something interesting, right?
- Yeah, international workers' day.
It's not celebrated in the US,
but in many other countries, it is.
- Right, on May 1st, a lot of people
have a day off, so that's always good.
- Yes.
- All right, so why don't we take a look
at some of the words that
we saw in this dialogue,
which were maybe a little bit different
or difficult in language takeaway?
- Language takeaway.
All right, we're just gonna look at
five words here and the first one.
We talked about the
genesis of the movement.
- Right, Genesis.
- Genesis.
- Okay, so many of you may know
that Genesis is a book in the Bible, right?
- That's right, not where
this word comes from.
It's the first book in the Bible.
- So it's the beginning or the origin.
- Origin.
- So that's a genesis, so the genesis
of our legal system, you would say.
- Right, or the genesis of this problem.
So it's the origin.
- Yeah, it's a little bit
of a formal word, isn't it?
- Yeah, I guess maybe you can
say the origin or the beginning.
- Yep, but maybe in an academic
setting, you can talk about the genesis.
- Yes, very good.
All right, what do we have next?
- Well, one of the reasons
why the workers movement
got started was because of
the appalling working conditions.
- Apalling.
- Apalling, if something is
appalling, it's shockingly bad.
- Very, very bad.
- Yeah, so now if something is appalling,
like the working conditions were appalling.
- That's right.
- The appeal appalled.
- Exactly, I'm appalled at your behavior.
- Okay, so it's almost
like you are disgusted.
- Yeah, that's right,
very, very strong word.
- Yeah, very strong.
- Okay, okay, so the working
conditions were appalling
and people were setting
up this movement, right?
But what happened?
- They met some hostility.
- Hostility.
- Hostility from the police, right?
- That's right.
- So what is hostility?
- Hostility is the state of
receiving an unfriendly reaction.
- Okay.
- It acted in a very unfriendly way and
it also suggests a hint of violence, even.
- Okay, yeah, yeah, so if
somebody is hostile, they
can maybe be aggressive
and maybe to a point violent.
- That's right, okay.
So a hostile person.
- Yeah, or a hostile environment,
a dangerous environment.
- Okay, hostility, hostile, very good.
- Yeah, now because of these
appalling working conditions,
the labor movement decided
to take drastic measures.
- Yeah, drastic measures.
This is a really wonderful
phrase and I think it would help us
to listen to a few examples
of this phrase in use.
- Example one.
- The president was faced
with some difficult decisions
and was forced to take drastic
measures to solve the crisis.
- Example two.
- The police took very drastic measures
to control the protesters outside
the government in the palace.
- So we understand drastic measures
as extreme actions or decisions, right?
- Yeah, exactly.
- I think there's a saying that says
desperate times called for drastic measures.
- No, desperate times
call for desperate measures.
- Uh-huh.
- Well, okay, but it goes
around there somewhere, right?
- Don't say like that.
- So if you really have an emergency,
you need to do something drastic.
- You have to take drastic measures
or you can even say take drastic action.
- Okay, very good and
what about our last word?
- After the protests ended in violence,
people started to get angry because
of the brutality, the police showed.
- Okay, brutality.
- Brutality.
- So again, maybe brutality and
hostility are maybe similar, right?
- A little bit similar.
So brutality is the state of
being harsh or very forceful.
- Okay, so brutality now.
We also use the word brutal.
- Right, so that means
harsh or very forceful.
- Now, sometimes we can use that word,
but not in a harsh or forceful way, right?
- Yeah, and it's quite, yeah.
I might say something like,
oh my god, that test was brutal.
- Uh-huh, it was brutal over.
- So it was really
hard or really difficult.
- Right, so that's what
you're saying with this word
that it's very hard or it was very intense.
- Yeah, maybe one more example.
- Okay, so for example, I can say, oh, I
went for a run today and it was brutal.
- So tired.
- So it was really difficult.
- Yeah, it was brutal.
- And Marco, is this something
that's used by everyone?
- That phrase brutal, using in that
context, would be for younger people, maybe.
Not really, you wouldn't really
hear older people using it like that.
- So it's a little bit slangy, yeah.
- Okay, all right.
- Great, great.
So those are five
interesting vocabulary words.
As Marco mentioned, we wanna look at
some more difficult structures
now in fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
Okay, so we have some
phrases that we saw in this
dialogue and well, let's
start with the first one.
- Well, the teacher opens his discussion
by talking about how an understanding
of the legal system is an important
aspect of being a good citizen.
- Okay, an important aspect.
- An important aspect.
- So well, maybe we know
the word important, right?
So what's his aspect?
- A part of something, an
important part of something.
- Okay, so the teacher started
with an important aspect
of and then specified the
idea or what part it belongs to.
- Right, so it usually follows this form.
Noun is an important aspect of noun.
- Okay.
- So for example, quality control is an
important aspect of keeping customers happy.
- Okay, perfect.
A part of, very good.
So aspect sounds a little bit more formal
or just a lot more intelligent, right?
- Yeah, professional.
And actually, it's a wonderful
way of setting up your idea.
- So the teacher said that
it's an important aspect
of understanding the legal
system was understanding
its origins or its genesis
and then she moved on
and said that it's not enough
to simply memorize laws.
- That's right, it's not enough
to simply do something.
- Okay, so the beginning of this sentence,
it's not enough to simply something.
By starting a sentence like this, you are
indicating that more is required, right?
- So here, it's not enough
to simply memorize the laws.
We're saying that most
people just memorize the laws,
but they need to go
further and understand them.
- Exactly.
- Another example would be, it's
not enough to simply pass your exams.
You must get good grades as well.
- Right, or maybe in a business context,
it's not enough to simply satisfy your
customers, you must impress them.
- Okay, very good.
So that's a very good
way of starting out this idea
of more is required.
- That's right, more is required.
- All right.
All right, well, I wanna move
on to one final point here.
I found this sentence to
be really, really interesting.
They passed a resolution
stating that eight
hours would constitute
a legal day's work.
- Okay, so why is this interesting?
- Well, I found that there's
two verbs going on here.
They passed a resolution that eight
hours would constitute a legal day's work.
So we've got two verb
times going on here at the
same time, and I'm wondering
about this one would.
- Okay, so what's happening here?
Obviously, this happened in the past.
It's like about 100 years ago, right?
- Right, so the resolution was
passed 100 years ago, right?
So this is going on in the past.
- Right.
- But there was a future action
that was going to happen
in consequence of this.
- Right, so the resolution stated
that eight hours would constitute.
So that's like the primary
action was the passing
of the resolution,
and the result is this
sort of, this event that
happens in the past,
but is a future event to
the first primary event.
Does that make any sense at all?
- So this is called the
future in the past, right?
- That's right.
- Okay, so it's a grammar structure.
Many of you maybe know the simple present
or the future tenses, but
this is a little strange one.
And as we said, so
maybe it's a little bit
difficult to understand
the grammar in general.
So why don't we take a
look at some more examples
of how we would use
this future in the past?
Example one, the president
said that he would cut taxes
by 5%.
Example two,
I made a promise that I
would not smoke anymore.
Example three,
Carl told me he would buy a new car.
Okay, so now I think
it's clear this whole idea
of the future in the past,
and we'll also be answering
any questions on the site if
you have any problems, right?
- That's right.
- Okay, so why don't we listen
to the dialogue one more time,
and then we'll come
back and talk about this
holiday, which is the
International Workers Day.
- All right, everyone, settle down.
Let's get started.
As you know, an important aspect
of becoming a good citizen is understanding
the genesis of our legal system.
It's not enough to simply
memorize our laws, it's
necessary that we comprehend
why and how they were formed.
This brings me to our topic for today.
Does anyone know what
we celebrate on May 1st?
- Sinkered in my own.
(audience laughing)
- I know, that's May 5th in Spanish, James.
No wonder you're failing my Spanish class.
No, May 1st is International Workers Day.
- Do we get a day off from school in?
- No, it is not considered
to be a national holiday
here in the US, but
in other countries it is.
- Oh man.
- In the 19th century, working
conditions were appalling,
with workers being forced to
work 10, 12 and 14 hours a day.
Support for the eight hour workday movement
was growing rapidly, despite the indifference
and hostility of many union leaders.
And by April 1886, 250,000 workers
were involved in the May Day movement.
Previous legislative attempts
to improve working conditions
had failed, so labor organizers
took drastic measures.
They passed the resolutions,
stating that eight hours would
constitute a legal day's work.
And on May 1st, 1886,
the resolution took effect.
- Cool, is that why we
only work eight hours now?
- Yes, but the happy
ending came at a high price.
On May 3rd, 1886, police
fired into a crowd of strikers
at the McCormick Reaper works
factory, killing four and wounding many.
A mass meeting was called for
the next day to protest the brutality.
- And then what happened?
- Well, as we say, the rest is history.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so Erica, in
Canada, do you celebrate this?
- We do, but not on May 1st.
- Oh, really, when is it?
- The first weekend in September.
- Oh, really, and why?
- Um, I am not 100% sure.
(laughing)
I think it's because we already
have a long weekend in May
because we sell it 'cause on the 24th
of May is the Queen Victoria's birthdays.
We have to celebrate that.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah, it can have two
vacations on the same month.
- Oh, wow.
Well, yeah, I mean, it's
not productive, right?
- Exactly.
What about an Ecuador?
- Yeah, we do on May 1st, it's a holiday
and we actually have
two holidays in May as
well because on the
24th, we actually celebrate
the Battle of Pichincha,
which is one of the
decisive battles for the
independence of Ecuador.
So we don't mind having two
holidays in the same month.
- Well, it sounds like
Ecuador is a better holiday.
(laughing)
It's definitely Canada, so it is.
- So yeah, on May 1st, people take vacations
and our companies, usually on May 1st,
will do something
special for their employees.
- Oh, that's kind of
a nice gesture isn't it?
- Yeah, so it's like it's workers' day, so
they'll set up maybe a barbecue or a trip
or something like that, so that's
what usually happens on May 1st.
- Great, well, what
about in your countries?
Listeners, do you celebrate May Day?
- May Day, May 1st, right?
And if you do, well, let us know.
Come to our website,
www.EnglishPod.
com and leave your questions
and comments there as well.
- That's right, well, thanks for downloading
this lesson and until next time, bye.
- Bye.
(upbeat music)